foreign
[Music]
action that is of the form
uh the integral is we calculating space
space time of some lagrangea
The Entity that's a function of uh some
scalar fields
and it's um
um and the last time I wrote the LeBron
June or uh the so-called pre uh Theory
um uh but you know generally uh you can
consider typically let's say second
order uh iterative term uh and we're
going to assume that this this
expression is is lorensive variant uh as
an example that we considered last time
but you know this this uh the formism
we're going to discuss is certainly
going to be a bit more General
um for now I'm just going to consider it
you know this uh
um and uh proceed with uh one of these
two different methods uh of uh
Equalization that if you don't correctly
are ultimately supposed to be uh you
know more or less equal to up to some
some of these organization that we have
included to important mechanical
um so
uh so the first so first discussion
uh in order to discussion
I would have to first understand uh the
classical mechanics of the field Theory
uh formism that is to say uh instead of
working with all the Grande equation we
need to describe uh the classical State
our system in terms of phase space and
the name space will be parameterized by
the
um minimize coordinates which in our
case is
um the field on the field five well at
the instance an instance of time uh so
um so here we do
uh I'm going to emphasize that in the
canonical momentum we're going to fix
the time okay
um
we're going to work at a strict internet
uh and a view by of X they're actually
in the single coordinate for different X
as infinite set of generous poignants
that's how we we went to all the Lebron
the questions
so there are uh the conjugates so these
are the genomical
uh coordinates
uh and uh
system with implemented there's 50 many
coordinates
um
what we call that generous coordinates X
is just an index
momentum
um one associated with every uh camera
is coordinate now strictly speaking to
do that uh following the usual clinical
problems will have a physical types of
systems uh for uh
but uh in this current uh what this can
be on field theory is a little bit more
convenient to just uh
um
this function of uh the Sphero point x
uh will be that you wrote it
um so in the in the usual mechanics will
be doing the lagrangea would describe
the time derivative of the
the time derivative of the um
okay so
um
so in the uh three Theory three scalar
uh theory for example
discussed last time uh there's a very L
at the kinetic term is just one half uh
Five Dot squared and in this case this
Pi will just be equal to
um
foreign
peritonia
density
um and uh
is uh
this will be everything will be just
sometimes
all right so um
it's easy to uh yeah it is another
custom to working with this kind of
Continuum of human density it's easy to
derive to recover the form of the
hamiltonian just like this without the
space
um
um any questions so far
oh sorry I forgot to say that of course
uh as usual
um it's uh it's understood that the
simultaneously is important it's
supposed to be viewed as a functional
not defined by that but not by and PI
right so so this is subject to the
astray or the this condition that um
they're supposed to solve
by that in terms of
pi
via the relation uh
right so uh for example in the free
scalar okay example
uh well last time so you can easily wake
this up uh and uh
is uh one half pi dot squared five plus
and we have a special derivative of five
uh squared and then the gradient of pi
squared uh plus the one half M Square
so in the country L I had a minus sign
for the last terms and that number is a
transformed
um
and uh then I'm supposed to replace this
by dots by the relation to Pi so this
can you tell me it I don't think in
terms of that minus infinity squared
plus uh some a second derivative of the
um now from the point of view of the
classical mechanics
um uh you know these especially
derivatives are just you know by
definition the difference between by a
different values of X and so this will
all be considered as part of the
potential
in the sense of classifications
any questions about this
um so uh
now that's not enough to specify the
Dynamics in the canonical communism In
classical mechanics
um well it's almost enough but to
complete it I need to say what the
Boston bracket is but of course that's
why the user definition for some
brackets uh is uh
so this uh implicitly this is always at
equal time we're talking about uh
quantities at given at a given time
um by x uh so I'm going to Omit amid the
time pointers
between the different momentum density
uh this is also zero
I I said just make it clear in case it's
not probably obvious that unfortunately
it's economic momentum this has nothing
to do with the actual momentum in the
sense of the uh you know consider
charging transaction symmetry you've
seen that in the homework that has
nothing to do with that emotional
canonical momentum here like a momentum
it's interesting is that it is uh
conjugate to the uh coordinates but in a
sense it wasn't right you know foreign
[Music]
x and x x Prime is uh
uh Delta function and yes
uh this is uh
quantization of the usual bottom bracket
for the system with a discrete uh
degrees of freedom Freedom
um
and uh and of course uh given this uh
then we can say that if you have some
general function or functional of the pi
and Pi uh on the currently s and cardio
G and then this is uh this Photon
bracket is just defined to be the
integral with back to the special
coordinates the function of integration
and that would start to i x something is
minus the same thing with the uh
any question at this point
and once you have that you know this is
all of the classical mechanics of the
spill theory is captured by this
equation
foreign
all right so uh any questions about so
so this is just uh you know as as
distributary classical mechanics all of
this uh would actually be equivalent to
the other
um underground equation well last time
in terms of uh uh you know dictating the
timing evolution of the field uh but uh
so here we reduce the parameterize the
standard system in terms of the very
space variables
um and uh there's a photographic of a
straightforward organization uh to the
quantum version of the theory
before we move on to the quantum theory
okay so uh now uh let's uh contacts
um well
um
uh the rule is the same as you know when
your first learned in uh quantity 10 you
know the mechanics we're going to
promote the uh phenology called
coordinates uh which are uh let me uh
still uh time coordinates uh but I want
to emphasize that uh in the final
formalism of course by construction the
time is on a very different footing as
space uh we're always going to
parametrize uh our state
um in terms of the these uh In classical
contexts in terms of these five advice
at a given time and in the quantum
context will be uh in terms of things
uh well uh we'll be talking about evil
time commentators to begin with
um so we're going to promote this canvas
hi
um
which are uh classical variables uh to
operators
The Operators uh you know them by the
hats uh if there's when there's a room
um and uh ads
next
um and by the by the usual rule of
canonicalization
uh
we
uh are going to
log in so I'm going to last because I
haven't actually been trying to help our
space on which this operator acts I'm
going to assume um the Hill fire space
exists and trying to infer this property
um after I understand uh these operators
as well as Hamilton so
um the uh by the usual group of clinical
conversation uh once you promote the
colonial coordinates economical momentum
so
um
to operators they are supposed to
satisfy uh equal time
equal time right because I'm about to
write it's not true
um
well we just replaced the Boston
brackets with uh commutator so Pi with
pi
X
[Music]
uh that I had
the specific pride I mean that they're
impossible to zero
uh and the uh I had
t x
and Pi at T
X Prime
minus infinity is not going to give us I
H bar uh the special Delta this is a
this is a density operators
uh and that's the that's the stressful
organization of the usual rule of
economic organization
depends on the continuous parameter
any questions about this
and of course as later as we perceived
it well and the ultimately the job is
um okay so uh no I want to emphasize
that up with this point in the
discussion of the uh this equal time
committer of these operators if I hadn't
hi-hat I haven't used any knowledge of
the hamiltonian right so there's no
Dynamic so far right I'm talking about
equal time commutators
um and so this is
supposed to apply so not just free video
Theory but also arbitrary interaction so
as long as
you are the only amount of errors
foreign
thank you
of course
you know then that actually transformed
into some more critical way
um with some instances but apart from
that you always have these spies and
bikes
um
there'll be some thought we went to
discuss stage Theory it's already the
end oh well that's right at the end but
then two times
but for now this is a business question
um all right
um okay so
um uh well uh good proceed uh it's going
to be convenient you know uh to uh
because to work with uh uh with uh
transforms for your recommendation
oh yeah transformed
I'm just going to consider operators at
a given time
something times e to the i k
dot X
is a special event there's no frequency
yeah
transform of course
um but I'm going to use a special
notation for that this I have I can also
of course
and write this as integral and P is
expression okay uh Sunday Times is
uh okay now I'm going to give some name
to
um
definition
for later convenience I'm going to write
the operator inside the bracket in a
specific way and
um and of course uh I've done the
problem set once you would uh have some
idea of where this might come from but
for now it's just going to be a
definition that is I can always rewrite
the the integrand the boy transform in a
way
uh well let me just write this thing
down and let me explain so I'm going to
write here AK plus a minus K there
um I haven't defined within a diverse
bar so this is going to be definition so
a plus a value a K plus a minus K dagger
is going to be defined to reply hand in
this way uh where does the UK here is
some arbitrary function
um I have I don't know I mean whatever
it is because this is if I make this
function I have a definition for this
combination of the base uh and here I'm
going to have a different combination AK
um minus a minus K
so by the middle a here I just mean some
operator that depends on payback is
whatever the the point this is just a
way to
rewind the the transform of the spine
and here
um I'll put in some normalization factor
to find something minus one times two
new k okay
so here
I mean our comments here
um so this are you okay
the the thing is uh for now
uh arbitrary
arbitrary function
functionality okay it has to be uh let's
say it to be real and positive in the
experiments but uh apart from that some
other function again speaking here just
as mineralization
uh nothing keeps going on here uh and uh
I'm allowed to write in this way uh
because you know I could call this
because I'm operator f i got this from
Opera G and I I take some combination I
call them a and data
furthermore the notation of the dagger
is such that if a backer minus K is
really the hermitian conjugate of a
minus a then it ensures the first
expression is permission
we sometimes are related
um
communication and also ensure the second
this idea is auto convention you can set
for the minus I here and there's a minus
the sign again verify that this is also
emission effective drugs okay so uh so
this expression I'm right now I'm here
uh and at this point you should just
view this you know these as a
so for now
for now
these are viewed as
definition
operators they generally may not be uh
it's just such a way to rewrite by hand
okay any questions up at this point
um just like the definition is motivated
by the way we want our careers to be
terminated like uh I don't really need a
motivation at this point I I'm just
going to do this I'm then I'm going to
study the commentator okay and do that
okay so so so so far I don't need I
don't I don't need to give a motivation
I I can I can I can define a diagrams
okay
um
all right
no uh now let's look at the commentary
advantage
um
um so let's look at the computation
relations so commentators
uh so uh you know of course A and A that
way you just do the inverse play
attachments okay in terms of if I
haven't I had it right then it's going
to be determined by by this definition
so uh since you know the current 500 Pi
hats you also know a with a direct so
let's look at that so what are the
common relations uh well first of all
can you see uh this combination AK plus
a minus K dagger is nothing but the
Fourier Transformer and at equal time
all the time has committed with one one
another and therefore the price will
also computers
so
um uh and therefore I know from the
first relation that a K plus a minus K
dagger with a K prime plus a minus K
Prime staggerator
it's can use
all right let's follow from high uh
exits
any questions so far
right no objectives
um well uh then I also know that iPad's
gonna be good I had a different special
finance and therefore although these AK
a minus a dagger here they all can be
with one another so let me write this
down uh AK
minus a minus a dagger a
um okay Prime uh minus a minus K Prime
for arbitrary tan K Prime
these two commute
um and then finally I have to compute
the the commentator of this guy a plus a
doctor here and a minus a value here
uh and uh that's easy again easy to to
work out uh and I'll just write an
answer and your stereotypes is obvious
and obviously it would be obviously be
correct so a K plus a minus K so I take
this for the top put a transform there
with the bottom this a a prime minus a
uh uh minus
this is equal to minus two Delta B minus
one
um uh K plus
uh well it's easy to plug into the very
pass if you take this and with that it
would have to change the variable this K
to K Prime here and uh you have into ikx
here you have i k Prime X Prime and if
you got that Delta function okay so it
says K Prime 3 minus K you're going to
integrate over that and produce Delta X
provide all these pre factors cancel and
the pre-factor arranged to cancel
because this was like one over square
root of mu which goes like square root
of U and they're going to cancel we sub
K to the equation and you can check the
factor too is
um any questions
um so uh now in addition to the third
equation I can write an authority
version which is usually uh equivalent
to the third one by exchanging K with K
Prime so if I swap the row of K and K
Prime uh and uh flip the the sign on
both sides I get the question that says
AK minus a minus K dagger with a K Prime
uh plus a minus a prime is equal to plus
two Delta
uh UK
accounts for free is everyone all right
okay uh any questions so far
uh so uh once you have these it's
obvious you can either subtract and then
again come into a with a and a Diagon so
equivalently we can add and subtract
these four uh equations and then we
conclude as you can see for example well
okay with AK Prime commute uh so there's
a that okay
fine and uh now surprisingly
um if you take okay
Prime
then that is equal to Delta okay minus
okay
yeah
now this conversation we have been done
in the first very first lecture and we
said that this is this is the
communication relation that is supposed
to be uh obeyed uh by uh creation and an
election operator of some identical uh
particles
um
in particular
um uh you know uh with the one Fargo
State normalizes some specific way so
that okay
all right so uh what we've learned so
far is that if you choose to write I had
if I had in this way in terms of n a
dagger a dagger obey comes in
relationships that would have been
Amazed by an attention Annihilation and
creation operators some party
uh that does not mean the AMA that are
actually unless
because just having a conversation
relation like this is not enough for
that interpretation
okay so so one more what more do you
need
uh well uh for one thing uh you will
need to know for a and a dagger to have
the determination as mentioned operator
of a particle uh you will need to know
that uh
uh so far we don't know what the vacuum
is because I haven't told you about 100
kilometers
all right so so so we did not know that
a dagger have interpretation as quick
and action operators they just have to
evade the same algebra and level of
coming in you're like
uh in fact I also haven't told you what
new case
I'm argue function of my choice so I
actually haven't even fixed my
convention for it yes
any questions so far
um
uh so
um let me make a uh uh make a side
comment
um
so remark
um I could have uh redefine an attacker
if I rescheding the city okay
suppose I do that
uh I will get some new kind of a pair of
you know things like hey that girl I
call them BMV
dagger uh in the same way but with the
rescale the new I would say that uh by
construction BK plus B minus K dagger
would be some we're scanning in fact
Orlando okay times AK plus a minus K
there
and uh uh b k minus B minus K okay would
be some one over Lambda k
uh a minus a k minus a minus K right so
um you know if I um
uh uh you know if I had rescale my view
I would produce some BNB dagger that's
related to a and a dagger in this way
but apart from that everything
everything will stay the same so you see
uh you can express for example obviously
you can express a decay in terms of AK
as Lambda K plus uh Lambda K uh inverse
uh over two
by by adding these Expressions right
okay
uh uh plus uh Lambda
um
plus uh Lambda K minus Lambda okay
inverse
over two a minus K uh that
foreign
if you want to interpret let's say a as
a particle an action operator if it
happens to be that a that's an eye of
the vacuum then we cannotize a vacuum
therefore B canal
UK
[Music]
okay so anyway the point that this
remark is that if you do this
transformation the bnbk B and B dag are
still obey the same company relation of
the of great International operator so
there's nothing you know too sacred
about this kind of General relation it's
very easy it's very cheap to produce
that this by the way is known as the
above review of transformation
uh I'm not going to discuss it's it's
this implication I'm just saying that
it's something you can do
um okay so
um so so far uh one thing I want to
emphasize is that there is no Dynamics
okay
this this expansion is going to be
General
any questions before we uh proceed to
discuss to them
um
by redefining them
this is this is the form of the bubble
device
it's slightly different but that's
really interesting it's basically linear
transformation that mixed with a mix a
and a dagger in such a way that you
still preserve uh the this kind of thing
okay
all right
um okay so uh
now let's discussed I haven't talked
um to uh to proceed I'm just going to
again study the simplest case first I
haven't told me a free uh sailor
uh field Theory and now I'll give that
as a Content operator
so uh well uh we're gonna proceed by uh
approach uh we're just gonna uh for now
we're gonna proceed by this naive uh uh
Replacements of the in the classical
hamiltonian and replace all the you know
the canonical coordinates and momenta by
the corresponding operator so Pi three
times pi hat and uh five equals five
hats
financing
I swear
all right so
um then uh you can plug in this way
transform the expression and evaluate in
terms of the Ana daggers
um and it's easy to you know two two
copies of that with the knk prime you
interpret.x you get a Delta function
says K the K Prime took me equal and
opposite and then you saw uh for um
um
uh one half
so from this term you're going to get a
a packer new k for two
um the the two the fact that the two Pi
will be gone after integrating on the
okay
excellent
um and uh then we've got AK uh minus a
minus K there
a uh
[Music]
and these natural terms combine in the
following
ways to the UK enter uh K squared plus N
squared
okay
plus a minus K Banker a a tiger plus a
okay so let's uh uh here you know this
case word the special case will come
from This this term and the stands for
it and not turn this to the minus
you can see that's the best
all right
um
so
I think at this point uh well that's
actually
into the side of the board because I
still want to give the top expression
thank you
um so now the expand is out you'll see
that there'll be some things like terms
like a dagger a dagger a but then
they'll also improvi terms like a a and
a doctor
um
all right so
if you want to uh
demand if you want a to not the thing is
up to this point we're free to True is
what UK is it's by definition uh but
Andrew UK such as a has a nice
interpretation
um uh so if I choose
um if I choose as you can see here
actually you can choose if you choose
new K to be the square root of K square
plus M squared
um uh then at least two times I have the
same uh
will have the uh
right we'll have the same conversion so
that the terms of a a will cancel okay
um when that happens uh it will be true
that uh you know the a actually a nice
vacuum
uh so uh
let me write this down uh so if we
choose
uh this is our definition of a which
looks listening could be a boy called
Omega K that is this square root of
Special K squared plus M squared
um then uh
this uh operator
you'll see that the a term cancel 8
diagram also okay so uh and uh
you have back a corner a corner here you
have a diagram a four times like that so
uh you're left with
Omega K AK not good
okay
uh plus uh well you have a negative a
but also a a dagger and I'm commuting is
a commentator to put it into this uh
normal ordered form if I do if I you
know especially take that as my
definition I I would you know produce a
common one hand the commentator of the a
with a dagger which is one half Delta V
minus one well the difference in their
momentum which is uh zero zero value
okay so that looks kind of bad uh
because this of course is uh
okay
uh
so so that that's the result we would
get uh by uh naively uh plugging uh you
know the by hand I had into the
classical expression
any question up to this point
yes
um uh you know you may not know that yet
uh well what can easily divide this
while classical of course you know you
follow from the regular motion because
the bottom bracket that location
important case as well so you can easily
improve that right I didn't say that but
it's really one line I mean
but yes
fine uh now uh of course you might uh
you might be bothered by this this
Divergence here
um but you know nobody says you know
this there's not anything you feel
sacred about this classical uh ordering
uh all right so uh uh you know what is
the what is the actual hamiltonian
operator is to it's up to us uh uh if
you want to study a specific uh
affordability uh so
um the real question is now given that
how many billionaire does that and I
feel here have the property that you
want uh namely uh you know conquerade
various and the causality and the
locality and all of that uh so
um Linda so the the correct statement
here uh as you have verified in your
problem one of problems at one that in
glory detail I resume
um my statement is that
without this thing
so uh I can just put the normal ordering
sign over everything
and that is actually the correct handed
on the end of device uh my vulnerable
Theory
uh in particular uh once I draw this
term this hamiltonian but that is a
vacuum
uh
the vacuums uh is not only time machine
invariant but it also will be fungally
there and of course this uh you know
something that you have seen in the
context of the homework problem uh and
uh furthermore from this you uh well you
also learned that uh AK uh is a
is going to lower the energy by Omega K
whereas AK dagger is going to raise
energy about Omega okay and
the vacuum is lowest energy State this
energy is going to be lowered further
and of course it has to be United by
okay
and then you can create all the
multi-particle states by taking this hey
daggers
and as a moment that I come back in and
also from a basis of your Huber space of
multiple States and the fact that this
adag is all committed with one another
have to do with that the fact that uh
the theory uh is is going to be free and
can be interpreted as a free particles
uh we'll come to that a bit later uh for
now I'll just say that once you
understand that the hamiltonians are
from a dagger a you will really know
that a and a dagger have the
interpretation as uh annihilating or
creative particles yes
foreign
space will be spanned by a basis of this
form uh and uh and the energy of that of
course it's all specified and and
um the the vacuum uh you know has to be
of Zero Energy in any pancare uh
invariant Quantum field here we said
this before because this is part of the
you know one correct group generators
um and uh to say the vacuum is invariant
uh partially this that should be
and you know uh as you have seen in the
homework problems
um anyway so so now I basically in this
discussion on the pre-fielder I ended up
back in where we were in the first
lecture in the first lecture
um I started with a system of three
particles I postulated that we have
these things uh and we can organize them
using this organization operator I can
do the hamiltonian uh from which I
construct a field operator this field
operator as you checked you know in a
homework problem a base this Punk array
a transformation property there's
another crucial property which I
mentioned the first lecture which is the
causality that the the space like
separate points commute I didn't verify
that in the lecture explicitly but we'll
come to this in more detail later yes
so right now what we have is like if we
look at the expression through the
company and operations what we have in
the draft is is we have opening next
week and when we integrate that over
space I get to think of things so why
are we just allowed to put normal
ordering on it this is the definition of
the operator
uh it's not that we are allowed the
question the question you should be
asking is not what is allowed uh the
question you're asking why is this the
correct definition
okay
but then why is it uh well not the whole
point of buying a homework is that the
resulting Theory satisfy the properties
that I want one filter in the bank that
is I have this local field Operator by
hand and then obey the property that the
transformed Covenant transformation can
you verify and that it based my
personality which you haven't learned
about okay but these are together with
some other uh things uh you know the
exist in human space and so forth on
this fact I can stay in the overspace
are the basic populates of quantity over
here and so when once you have
all right
you can make your health and
inconvenient to like not have terms like
challenges
um well in this case uh you know the
multiplication in the view is quite
popular to make the hamiltonian behave
nicely you see first of all stop
cracking this constants of course it
doesn't affect any computational
relationship
so all of the time Evolutions that will
be dedicated by the naive Communicator
will be unexpected
um and uh at this point I would say that
uh that's just uh you can take that as a
definition of our Theory there's a
definition of the three together here
um uh we'll sort of discuss what happens
when we type interaction but generally
the point is that if you either write a
hamiltonian it better at least be what
you find I can back here all right so so
this you know on the vacuum you have
zero energy uh then uh then the
hamiltonian should be of some normal
water reform uh and without that yeah
you can always choose to bring the a
daggers in front of A's
um but um
uh
um
uh you know but in general uh you know
if you have that uh interactive Theory
uh where you might have additional terms
you know like eight dagger squared a
squared or a to the board or indirect
support and things like that
um uh you know you have to
operator
that's really how you define it the
question of how you do what what is the
definition of responding mechanical
system
so as I've said this before Equalization
generally the procedure conversation is
ambiguous we are always it's always
possible by something else
um uh and that is associated with an
ordinary ambiguity but not restricted to
that's what it would be good
um and uh Now by General Quality
Mechanical model you need some
additional physical principle to fix
what is that it turns on vulnerability
uh things are more restricted because
quality emphasized it's a very small
page upon a mechanic where you have
additional signature something you have
additional constraints that is
representative volcanic and uh because
of these constraints not everything goes
uh if you try to add to this hamiltonian
things like you know a diverse squared a
squared
yeah you have to be extremely clever to
be able to end up with the results
yeah
it looks like this is
I I hope
this point
um so
I guess
in terms of like detection
pies are mostly speaking about defined
operators
um but their products are not that's
what I want me to say it uh strictly
speaking uh in this if you want to be
mathematical python python not by its
body but operators they're known as
operabatic distributions and 100 million
universities
um oh it will come to something related
to this idea but uh
yeah that's essentially the Source
because normally if you have a
well-defined you know linear operating
over space
um you can activate one over again
without algorithm results
um all right
um
any other questions
um okay so uh now finally let me uh so
far I'm specifically talking about uh
this time uh now we can evolve uh this
five from Tigo zero to General T uh
using the equation of motion
so
using this uh and not for any of the f
is I over H bar no not H bar I uh H has
something with f
uh we had uh we can determine
um
the assigned dependence
by uh at the next uh and this pie at
the X uh so I'll just rewrite the
results for let's write the result for
uh by on this board uh by the way at
this point I'm going to
um so this is scale for free yeah so now
when I'm claiming about time evolution
of what I'm using this oh yeah this is
only valid for the physical Theory
[Music]
now this is going to be the um product
I'll say what that means in just a
moment well I mean I've seen this in the
homework but uh
let me just explain this
matter so uh here
first okay not X
all right this K not X this is the the
uh when I don't write the arrow I always
mean the minkowski and Dot product
unless I'm talking about the liquidity
context book which we're not doing at
the moment so this is defined to be okay
and I'm done with x minus
Omega K
there's no independent K zero in this in
this formula so this is
replaced by this
um
of course if you can view this uh
Omega K forget to the K as the the
calcium Vector uh that correspond to the
energy momentum vector
[Music]
so um today
uh so this now is a Formula that of
course we have seen in the first lecture
and you have also seen in your homework
and then your homework you have it
verified uh the statement that uh if you
perform okay
transformation uh minus U
H
operator so we use your operator and
then acts on this by hand
uh in such a way that it takes my hand
to apply a Lambda X if I had experts if
I had a valentine
um
okay
any questions about this
um so that's all I'm going to say about
repeal Theory from the organization
we'll have a lot more to say about
interacting with field Theory from
chemical conversation but for now I'm
going to turn to the patently row
approach unless there's questions
foreign
um so
um this would be something for my
expected function and uh then you know
we're instructed to calculate some kind
of uh expression value by inserting
operators in functions in the world
um so
um but when we speak organization we
would like to be able to construct the
Hillary space so
um yeah we can imitate what we do with
same Quality Mechanical system with
finally many degrees of freedom
um
uh so uh we can
how can we represent a state let's say
uh in the Uber space so this
coordination is that Hillary state is
not an electricity
over space on the physical States
um
well
um uh remember uh in the way we first
derived the password
mechanics was that we impose some
boundary conditions at the initial time
of time uh and that practice was
supposed to calculate some kind of time
Evolution uh operate a matrix element
between some image and final state in
this initial final space are where they
were positioned eigensics
in this context with me eigensteins with
respect to
um it already gets by equalizing the
canonical coordinates namely the high
hands
before
um so
uh equal R2 uh
if you are through
um
uh to write a analogous expression for
wave function that you're familiar with
in your undergrading poly mechanics
class
here is a wave function
uh well be a function of
um
we function of buy at some given time
so there will be some function of Phi at
uh some fixed time so this is fixed time
t 0
um but with an enable with the previous
label which
so this is now a wave functional
so it is
um if you don't know what this is
um you know always space
I believe that at least approximately
um
so
bye
analogy
the display space you can really produce
your business directly like the same
derivation as we did in the second
lecture uh that um the
functional integral now the function of
integral is not this over Phi is a
function I but also depends on this
spatial uh coordinates X Vector which
are the labels for these different set
of components technology coordinates
um uh and uh
before so we want to set some
uh some initial and final boundary
conditions and final time the f
uh this is some if let's say
that's there's an initial plan TI
is
at a given time right so this is going
to depend on all the spatial coordinates
um and then we have e to the I times the
action I said H bar to one uh once again
integrating the time index Zero from PI
to GF recipe
uh so this happened as well this
functionality growth is supposed to
calculate what does it calculate okay
well as we know before I just calculates
the time you've looked and operator from
pi to the edge
we can write this in terms so this is
element of this this operator is just e
to the minus i h hat uh times e f minus
the I
States well they are specified by F now
this by I
what I find F Well finally an analog of
this position states your undergraduate
one mechanics class right so
um but that sounds a little bit weird
um because
um
write the same words so what is my eye
my eye is
a private States
uh we're back to the generalized
coordinates operator
well that what is an operator is I can
stay with respect to
the operator
uh I had X
well what is I had effects uh one point
of of a pathway pronunciation uh it is
uh this thing is
by Halifax is defined by a
insertion
hi X in the package
and so for example if I'm to calculate
um uh some well if I were to replace
this by some if I had some X acting on
the state obviously insert the pi of X
is in the average and by advising third
will be intuition variables haven't
operated so I want to clarify the
conceptual distinction or the closely
related to the operator which I want
from minus 5.
this is the same as what we're doing in
the simple Quantum becoming model and
just adding some extra indices
um all right
um all right then further by analogy
right this fine hat is the analog of the
like the underground mechanical class or
in the beginning of our of our our
course this Q hat this amount of the Q
Hands So this thing is supposed to act
on the state or the wave function
um by
uh wow it's supposed to be eigen this is
this wave function uh let's call it uh
um
uh
well uh let's say this way
um by definition uh you know if you have
two hats I can wave function a few uh
it's just you should the resulting wave
function is just Q times the wave
function so this is just five
I guess I switched that one there
yeah
I guess it might not sound I switched
the ability with an X hopefully that's
not going to cause any confusion
whatever it is
thank you
all right
um
so that's how the accent in general
um uh wave functional I suppose that
container wave function though
um so uh but now what what is this guy
this guy here this is supposed to be
eigenstate with back to uh if I had it
actually Andrew all right uh the I can
say
that means it's way functional
it's supposed to be a Delta function
so this is this is supposed to be
proportional to a function of Delta
function or Delta functional I suppose
uh it's really a functional Delta
distribution whatever that is
uh Pi Delta Phi minus
this is very schematic
um
this just means that it's unfunctional
that is supported some kind of
distribution in the functional sense you
send the functional integral that is
supported exactly at Phi equals five I
and vanishes elsewhere in this in this
infinimental space of functions
yes
uh so far I'm only defining uh the way
functional and I think was Zero
um uh
oh I I think I I see what we're asking
uh yes in fact uh that's a good point I
should have uh I should have written
this at zero
correctly
but
very good all right
yes so basically here we're just writing
me this the what how we expect five x to
x on a general function
and then and then we first completed
questions
uh look everything is the same as your
your antibioticon class all I did all
I'm doing is I I put some index on the
Queue and the index I call it X
everything is literally the same
okay so replace this by Q hats and this
is request sign of Q you might recognize
this it's just a skill had a wave
function it's just Q times
exactly that that's the definition of
the uh exactly the definition of the the
Q hats operator uh in terms of using in
the wave function representation
and the second this just says what is is
what is eigenstead
um what is the eigen way functional with
back to this Outlet
right
right and I've done nothing new right
I'm just you know but
I'm just putting some Index this text
hat X Vector I'm excuse so how does i i
x Define
oh
okay
uh you know it's just a simple
organization of what you do in the case
to take the vitamins literally I'm just
changing the patients of it but there's
nothing new
but uh as you might imagine but to
actually make sense of this expression
you've had to regulate as we have
experienced and then that would not be
easy okay so in fact uh to regularize
these with function notes okay uh in
which way to this realize uh you know
your space you can do that but uh if you
describe space you will break the
Manifest uh Lawrence uh symmetry I kind
of maybe partially between the purpose
of using the feeling of running focus on
the bracelets
um which is not very it's not ideal
there's something you can do but it
sound ideal
um and uh indeed uh it is quite a mess
so typically to deal with this wave
function host and in a manual approach
we are going to mostly avoid working
directly with the wave functions instead
as you have already have some experience
the quantity simple quantum mechanical
model we're going to study something
that's easier to calculate in this
topical language which is um vacuum
expression value of uh product a string
of operators like that so like the
product two hands now you are familiar
with
um okay so so these are the observables
uh that I will focus on and from these
observables uh in the previous one
mechanical model you have seen that from
those uh Q hat Q hats correlated wrong
State correlator you can extract
information about the spectrum of the of
the query that is also true molecular
theory
um uh but we can extract many uh things
uh observable is not just the energy
spectrum of particles but also things
such as the scapular Matrix which will
Define in the field lectures
um
uh okay
um so let me at least uh say this in
words
um I won't be able to finish this
discussion here but uh okay and say
something in words
um so it will be
more convenient
to uh to to study
uh imagine
highlighters
as you recall from my discussion in the
uh not single one mechanical model
um uh from the patio approach using the
which rotation with the help of the weak
rotation we can calculate easily or
preventively easily uh at least in
partitions back in correlators of this
type without thinking too much about uh
the boundary conditions we just need to
know we just need to say that this
specific question in time goes off to
imaginary time in the future and acts on
this situation Contour the device the
action
um
well
yeah actually let me see
um
yeah I think I better
not say anything further otherwise you
will take more require more time to uh
to uh
to clarify so uh
yeah so I don't quite have the time to
explain the connections of this to the
euclidea or the Wayward
which appears in uh problem two in the
current problem says
um but uh you can more or less guess
what is going on by straightforward
generalization of what you did in uh
simple funding mechanical model
previously uh just by you know adding
every time you see p you add this
additional indices of the spiritual
coordinate X and nothing more or less
works the same way
um but uh you know there's going to be
um a bit subtle key in terms of uh
calculating uh this kind of General
correlators uh in the lawrencian
segmentation space where the operators
have come with some arbitrary ordering
um and as we said uh the expectation
then let me just comment on
um so the expectations
is that if these five hands are truly
well defined local field operators they
should have made a property that
uh and two different points uh they will
convince uh whenever
they are the two points are space like
separated that is
that's inspired special point is that
I'm going to difference is where
um if there's space like separated this
will all commute uh in which case
um it wouldn't matter uh but either
their time like separated the ordering
does matter okay
um uh I guess uh next time I'm going to
explain uh
I mean I actually said this already
mechanical example
if you can try to figure out how to
generate license in this case but I'll
discuss this symptomatically next time
but how to uh produce this from
happening and roughly speaking you want
to insert Pi of x1.xn in the path
integral but those files are different
variables there's no one in any model so
you have to produce some ordering and
this order has to do with all your truth
um the calculation to the complex time
okay uh I I've mentioned this before but
I'll come to this I think what's this
matter the next time and we'll see that
it is particularly convenient so using
to use a math they want to calculate
this fully with rotating correlated that
is if I
um if I order the if I only continue all
the time to imagine time uh and also
amount of time in some particular way as
was um
uh stated before and finally Canada
model
um you will be able to calculate this
euclidean version of the coordinator uh
from the nuclear impact in which case
there's no backup I I think it's working
it would be simple to calculate
um and then you can always uh and then
continue the results uh back into the
lowest signature and actually recover
this kind of query function of arbitrary
given ordering to put it on five perhaps
and I'll explain how that works
today
I haven't looked at it
um somewhere I read
um
but yeah
foreign
all right
okay